tboholidays.com 2018-11-17

# TBO Holidays

**Overview**

This Privacy and Cookie Policy (the "Policy") becomes effective for all users from the date 15th May 2018. 

We, Tek Travels DMCC. Operating through our flagship brand " **TBO Holidays** ", a corporation incorporated under the laws of the UAE as the data controller ( "TBO," "We," Or "us "),  explain in this Policy how we collect, process and/or use information that we receive via our websites, emails we send, and mobile applications (collectively, the "Platform") that link to this Policy, as amended from time to time. This Policy describes how TBO collects, processes, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide. It also describes your choices regarding use, access, and correction of your personal information. For purposes of this Policy, personal information shall mean any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. 

This Policy applies only to information we collect, process and use through the Platform. This Policy does not apply to information that we collect through other channels, such as information that we collect offline, from other websites or from emails you send us.

**Information We Collect**

We collect information about you to provide our services. In order for us to best provide our services to you (and to help make it feasible for us to do so), it is essential that we are able to collect and use the information as described in this Policy. This means that the data collection is largely necessary for fulfilling the relationship we have with you, and where that is not the case, we have a legitimate interest in collecting the information described below.

**Information You Give Us**

When you fill out online forms, provide traveller or booking information, or provide us with other personal information actively, we collect that information for processing and use in accordance with this Policy. TBO may change its offerings, products and features from time to time, the options you have to provide us with personal information also may change, but here are few illustrations through which we collect personal information as provided by you: 

  * When you register on our site;
  * When you create an account;
  * Signing up for email alerts;
  * Completing a form related to one of our products or services;
  * Uploading various documents required for identification;
  * Contacting us for technical support or customer service;

Depending on how you interact with our Platform, the personal information we collect from you may vary. For example, to create an account we may ask only for an email address and password. In other circumstances, on signing up with us as an agent, we may ask you to provide other information, which may include your name, phone number, and/or postal address. We also collect and store certain information associated with actions you take. For example, when you perform a search on our site, we store such search information, information provided by you through online forms, IP addresses among others. We also store information about the bookings performed or offers availed, the time and duration of your activity on our Platform, and other information about your behaviour on our Platform. 

On our Android platform, when you set up an individual user account, you may create a profile  (a "Profile") that will include personal information you provide. At your request, we will create your Profile with information we extract from details you have entered on the Platform. When you fill out and save your Profile, your saved Profile can be viewed only by authorized TBO employees. 

If you enter credit card information on the Platform in connection with a booking, that information is sent directly from your browser to the third-party service provider we use to manage credit card processing and we do not store it on our servers. The service provider is not permitted to use the information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf.

**Information We Collect Automatically**

When you use the Platform, your device is automatically providing information to us so that we can customize our response to you. The type of information we collect by automated means generally includes technical information about your computer, such as your IP address or other device identifier, the type of device you use, and operating system version. The information we collect also may include usage information and statistics about your interaction with the Platform. That information may include the URLs of our web pages that you visited, URLs of referring and exiting pages, page views, time spent on a page, number of clicks, platform type, location data (if you have enabled access to your location on your mobile device), and other information about how you used the Platform. 

**Automated means of data collection include the following:**

**_Cookies And Tracking Technologies._**

Technologies such as cookies, locally shared objects  (sometimes called "flash cookies"), mobile identifiers and similar technologies ("Cookies") are used by TBO. We use Cookies to remember users’ settings as well as for authentication and analytics. These technologies may be used in analysing trends, administering the Platform, tracking users’ movements around the Platform and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. You can control the use of Cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable Cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service. For more information on Cookies, how we use them, the third parties we work with who use them, and how you can control them, please see the section entitled Cookie Policy. 

**_Log File Information._**

Log file information is automatically reported by your browser or mobile application each time you access a website on our Platform. For example, when you access our website, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends when you visit any website. These server logs include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, and pages viewed.

**_Device Information._**

We collect information about the device you use to access the Platform, including type of device, operating system, settings, and unique device identifiers, and IP address. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings. We collect the device type and any other information you choose to provide, such as username, geolocation, or email address. We also use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile software on your phone. This software records information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

**How We Use Information/Purposes**

We use the information we collect to provide our services. In order for us to best provide our services (and to help make it feasible for us to do so), it is essential that we are able to collect and use the information as described in this Policy. It is largely necessary for fulfilling the relationship we have with you, and, where that is not the case, we have a legitimate interest in using the information we collect, including personal information, for these purposes:

  * to provide you with relevant content;
  * to customise and improve the features, performance, and support of the site;
  * to transmit your booking and save your preference details;
  * for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, and service improvement (this includes use of your IP address and mobile device information to help diagnose problems with our service and to administer the Platform);
  * to communicate with you or initiate communication with you on behalf of third parties through your TBO account or through other means such as email, telephone (including mobile phone), or postal mail, including through the use of contact information that you provide to us or (where it is lawful for us to do so);
  * to analyse use of the Platform and improve the Platform;
  * to create aggregate statistical data that does not identify you individually (we use mobile device data and IP addresses to gather demographic information);
  * for other purposes that you separately authorise as you interact with TBO.

When we collect any information that does not identify you as a specific natural person ("Non-Personal Information"), we are permitted to use and disclose this information for any purpose, notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Policy, except where we are required to do otherwise by applicable law. If we combine any Non-Personal Information with your personal information (such as combining your ZIP code with your name), we will use and disclose such combined information as personal information in accordance with this policy. Similarly, if applicable law requires that we treat certain Non-Personal Information as personal information, we will use and disclose this information as personal information in accordance with this policy.

**Cookie Policy**

This Cookie Policy describes how TBO.  ("we", "our", "us") uses Cookies and similar technologies. For more information on our general data privacy practices, please see the full Privacy Policy. 

**_Cookies_**

Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored on your computer, mobile phone, or other device when you first visit a page. We use cookies, locally shared objects (sometimes called "flash cookies"), mobile identifiers and similar technologies ("Cookies") to help us recognize you on the Platform, enhance your user experience, understand usage of the Platform. Cookies may also be sent by other websites or services that run content on the page you're visiting. After you register on the Platform, we may collect information received from you. The provision of your data via Cookies is voluntary except for those Cookies that we place on your device because we need them for the performance of our Platform and our services.

**_What types of Cookies do we use?_**

We use two types of Cookies on the Platform: "session cookies" and "persistent cookies." Session Cookies are temporary Cookies that remain on your device until you leave the Platform. A persistent Cookie remains on your device for much longer until you manually delete it (how long the Cookie remains will depend on the duration or "lifetime" of the specific Cookie and your browser settings).

**_What are Cookies used for?_**

Cookies transmit information about you and your use of the Platform, such as your browser type, search preferences, personal information, data relating to links that have been displayed to you or that you have clicked on, and the date and time of your use. With the exception of an identifier Cookie that we associate with registered accounts to prevent fraud by members of the Platform, Cookies link to certain unique information that you entered at time of registration or on your profile, but this is not linked to your name.

**_We use Cookies for things like:_**

We use Cookies to help us determine whether or not you've signed in to the Platform and to keep you signed in during visits as you access different pages.

**_Security_**

We use Cookies to enable and support security features, prevent fraud, and protect your data from unauthorised access.

**_Preferences and Feature_**

We use Cookies to enable features and help us provide you with personalised content, such as showing you relevant offers and promotions

**_Analytics and Performance_**

We use Cookies to analyse how our visitors use the Platform and to monitor site performance. These Cookies help us to identify and fix errors, understand and improve services, research and test out different features, and monitor how our visitors reach our sites.

**Opting Out of Cookies**

We use Cookies that are necessary for us to provide the services you use and you cannot opt out of these Cookies on the Platform. You may be able to disable placement of some (but not all) Cookies by setting your browser to decline cookies, though this may worsen your user experience. Additionally, you can also control, manage and/or delete cookies via your browser settings.

If you enable location data for our Android Application, we may capture your location data. In such instances, we do not share your location with any other third Parties. You may disable location services at any time in your device privacy settings.

**Do Not Track Signals**

We do not currently respond to 'do not track' signals and similar settings or mechanisms. When you use the Platform, we try to provide a customized experience.

**Other Important Privacy Information**

If you wish to access, correct, update or request your personal information, you can do so at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided under "Contact Us" section on our site.

You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the "unsubscribe" Or "opt-out" link in the marketing emails we send you. If you are an unregistered user, or to opt-out of marketing you may contact us using the contact details provided under the "Contact Us".

Similarly, if we have collected and processed your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we reserve the right to keep any information in our archives that we deem necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

**Choices Regarding Your Personal Information**

In addition to your rights outlined above, if you are a registered user on our site, you can manage your account settings in the "Account Settings" page on the Platform where we provide you with the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personal information used for certain purposes.

We will send you notifications and if, and to the extent, you have opted-in to receive promotional communications, or other messages using the contact information (e.g., your email address, your mobile device identifier) you provided to us when you registered or when you requested information from us. You may opt-out of continuing to receive optional messages by following the instructions included in each message. Also, you can control most of the emails you receive from us by editing your email preferences within "My Account" settings on the site; provided you will need to separately opt-out of receiving our various emails by unsubscribing to each email that you have originally subscribed to. You can control the mobile push notifications within the "settings" section of the mobile app.

We will send you service-related announcements when we believe it is necessary to do so. In some cases, you can stop or limit the information we collect by automated means. To learn more about how you may be able to stop or limit our receipt of that information please review the section entitled Cookie Policy.

**Closure of account**

If you'd like to close your TBO account, you can do so within your Account Settings on the Platform. When you close your account, you will no longer have full access to its features, but we reserve the right to keep any information in a closed account in our archives that we deem necessary to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

**How Long We Keep Your Personal Information**

We keep your personal information only so long as we need it to provide the Platform to you and fulfill the purposes described in this Policy. This is also the case for anyone that we share your personal information with and who carries out services on our behalf. Retention periods can vary significantly based on the type of information and how it is used. Our retention periods are based on criteria that include legally mandated retention periods, pending or potential litigation, our intellectual property or ownership rights, contract requirements, operational directives or needs, and historical archiving. When we no longer need to use your personal information and there is no need for us to keep it to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements, we’ll either remove it from our systems or depersonalize it so that we can't identify you.

**Security Safeguards**

We employ physical, electronic, and managerial measures to safeguard the information we collect online. However, no company can fully eliminate security risks, so we cannot make guarantees about any part of our services. You are responsible for keeping your username and password secret. Once you have registered with us, we will never ask you for your password. Please create a unique password for your TBO account and do not use it for any other web services or applications. Do not share your password with anyone else.

**Data Control**

The information about you that we collect, process and/or use through the Platform is controlled by Tek Travels DMCC, at 2408, Oaks Liwa Heights, JLT Dubai P.O Box 34544. The privacy protections and the rights of authorities to access your information in other countries may not be the same as in your home country.

**You may reach us here**

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact us at [legal@tboholidays.com](mailto:legal@tboholidays.com)

**Updates to Our Privacy Policy**

We may revise this Policy from time to time by posting an updated version on the Platform. This version of the Policy will be effective for you as described at the beginning of the Policy. Further revisions of this Policy will become effective as follows: The revised Policy will be effective immediately for unregistered users and users registering accounts or otherwise acknowledging the Policy on or after the revision date. For other users who registered accounts before the revision date, it will also become effective immediately. However, they can object to the new Policy within thirty (30) days after the revision date. If we make a change that we believe materially reduces your rights or increases your responsibilities, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We may provide notice of changes in other circumstances as well. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. Your continued use of the Platform is subject to the most current effective version of this Policy.

**Contact Us**

**Tek Travels DMCC.**

**Attn: Legal Department**

**Email :[legal@tboholidays.com ](mailto:legal@tboholidays.com)**
